Jacek Smoter

jac.smoter@gmail.com ❖ tel. +48 603633655 ❖ Warsaw, Poland ❖ GitHub

I am looking for my first full-time job as a front-end developer. For almost a year I've been learning how to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and now - TypeScript. My projects and open-source contributions can be found on my GitHub. As of now, I'm focused on facing new challenges, gathering commercial experience, practicing what I've learned so far and developing my skills in those areas as well as in new ones. Before I've decided to dedicate myself to software development I've worked at a mental health NGO and, for over 10 years, as a freelance photographer.

EXPERIENCE

Photographer - freelancer www.jaceksmoter.com

2009 - Now

- Main focus on event photography: weddings, family, cultural, sports, political, also portrait, product and architecture.
- Forming and maintaining relations with clients throughout the whole flow, from understanding their needs, through creation of the photographs on the site or in a studio, post-production in close cooperation with the client, all the way to delivery and gathering feedback.

Warszawski Dom pod Fontanną

Feb 2020 - Aug 2022

Generalist at a Clubhouse - a self-help facility supporting people living with mental illness

- Support for Clubhouse members on their way to healing and independence both directly, one emotional and practical levels, as well as by providing research on help available in their environment.
- Co-creation of a community by empowering members in their initiatives, facilitation of meetings, continuous search for ways to strengthen the community focused on restoration and healing through meaningful relationships and focus on each person's potential.
- Representation of our Clubhouse at the World Clubhouse Seminar 2021 as a panelist along with staff and members of other Clubhouses.
- Tech support to the organisation and its members, including key role in transition to all-new remote approach to community-building during the COVID-19 pandemic. It allowed maintaining strength of our community and continuous support to its members during that time.

LoveKraków.pl 2012 – 2014

Photojournalist and head of photography department

- Management of team of photojournalists (up to five people), delegation of tasks
- Photography production, cooperation with people and organisations
- Creative, editorial and conceptual decision-making aimed at delivery of high-quality content at the expected time

EDUCATION

Jewish Studies 2014 – 2019

MA - University of Warsaw

BA - Jagiellonian University, Cracow

International Relations / Strategic Studies

MA and BA - Jagiellonian University, Cracow

2010 - 2016

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- **Technical skills:** Well-versed in HTML, CSS (vanilla, SASS, Tailwindcss), JavaScript, React and many tools nad libraries related to them. Right now working on understanding of TypeScript. Had some contact with testing using Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress. Also good with Microsoft Office Suite, Google Apps (including search!), Canva, Adobe apps, Windows and MacOS.
- **Soft skills and abilities:** open, inclusive communication; thoughtful question-asking; listening to and supporting others; creating and documenting processes; helping in non-judgemental way; being on time; striving to be well-organised; exploring and learning new tools; noticing and understanding possibilities and limitations, finding solutions fitted to them
- Languages: Polish (native), English (C1), Hebrew (A2), German (A2), Yiddish (A2)
- Interests: Building healthy relationships, making world a better place. Also my dog, video games, photography, collage-making, learning more about history of Jews in Poland, "Twin Peaks" and "Star Wars"